# Bhumi Padodara

## ETL / Data Developer

## **Contact Info**

Fairfax, Virginia, USA

+1 571-490-1821

padodarabhumi.k@gmail.com

## **Skills**

MS SQL SERVER 2012/2014/2016

SSRS, SSIS, MySQL, MS ACCESS

T-SQL, Query Analyzer, BCP, TOAD SQL Agent, SQL Profiler

Tableau, Power Bi, Informatica

IIS 8.0,8.5,10, TFS, JIRA, SVN, Visio, MS Office, Outlook, DB Designer

VB.NET, C#

## Languages

English

Hindi

Gujarati

#### Interest









## **SUMMARY**

Have 4+ years of experience in design, development, coding and testing of business/commercial applications in MS SQL Server 2016/2014/2012/2008, MS Access, and Windows 2000/2003/2010

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist in SQL Server 2012

Working knowledge of Software Development life Cycle (SDLC)

Experience in Creating Tables, Views, Triggers, Cursors, Dynamic Stored Procedures, User Defined Functions and other Transact-SQL (DDL, DML) statements for various applications

Very Good knowledge in Data warehouse star schema and snow flake schema data model and fill data using **ETL process** using SQL Server integration service.

Transformed data from one server to other servers using tools like Bulk Copy Program (BCP), Data Transformation Services (DTS)

Good understanding of Normalization /De-normalization, Normal Form and database design methodology.

Extensively experience in development of **T-SQL scripts**, MS Integration Services, Stored Procedures and views for business logic implementation, different kind of join to fetch the data from different table.

Excellent knowledge in RDBMS concepts and Data warehouse Concepts.

Installed and Configured SQL Server 2008/2005.

Created cluster index and non-cluster on tables and disable them before inserts and enable when inserts completed.

Strong troubleshooting and organizational skill, independent, self-managing and teamwork.

Ability to work in-groups as well as independently with minimal supervision.

## **EDUCATION:**

- Master's in Computer Science [GPA: 4/4]
   Virginia International University, USA (May 2018- Current)
  - Master's of Engineering in Computer Engineering [GPA: 3.30/4.0]

    Gujarat Technological University, India (June 2012- June 2014)
- Bachelor's of Engineering in Computer Engineering [GPA: **3.85/4.0**] **VVP Engineering College**, India. (June 2006- June 2010)
- Completed Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Certification (Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012 (70-461))

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Advantmed LLP, India

May 2017- April 2018

#### Role = Database Developer

**Project Description:** Healthcare information management company based in USA that helps health plans and managed care organization's optimize revenue and improve quality outcomes. Company also provides risk adjustment solutions for health plans.

#### Responsibilities:

- Created T-SQL objects and scripts used to maintain data integrity across all databases throughout database servers (Stored Procedures, Triggers, Functions)
- Wrote stored procedures using temp table, CTE for different business logics
- Performance tuning and query optimization of stored procedure for different products in SQL and MySQL
- Import flat files into SQL using SSIS based on fixed length column
- Centralized backup system using PowerShell
- Analyzed reports for long running queries, locks, deadlocks, backup history check and retention.
- Build Automation using SSIS package combine with JIRA tickets
- Build SSIS package for HEDIS test data creation in healthcare industry
- Established techniques for data transfers, built and maintained SSRS, ETL packages
- Created SSIS package to combine flat files data into single file
- Worked with PowerShell for scheduling all server backup
- Error handling with PowerShell to combine and store in one server
- Automated email for error and warnings
- Automation of release process (Development to test, test to UAT and UAT to production)
- Worked with transaction replication
- Created clustered and non-clustered indexes for optimization
- DBA related activities like monitoring load, temp database size check, shrinking database
- Troubleshoot errors in SQL server

## I-Engineering Software Pvt. Ltd, India

November 2015- May 2018

### Role = Software Developer (SQL Developer)

**Project Description:** Develop a product which is used in insurance companies (BNR, Concorde, Monarch) based in USA and UK, maintain database servers and support application programs for administrative, Web and mobile systems using .net and related tools and enhance the product as per client requirement. Analysis of coding, testing and debugging is done.

#### Responsibilities:

- Wrote stored procedures for Backup and copy to remote servers in all database servers
- Wrote VB script for delete unnecessary backup files from every database server
- Created complex SQL statements using joins, sub queries and correlated sub queries, Database
   Triggers
- Scheduled tasks using windows scheduler and SQL agent job for backup
- Created CLR for File and I/O Operation
- Import-Export Using BCP
- Automation using Batch files and window scheduler
- Wrote code for build version Automation process

- Created SSIS package using dynamic connections with many servers by configuration files based on condition
- Designed and developed **Packages with Dynamic tables** of Source and Destination
- Maintained database servers for database backup, check & maintain space on disk, check for backup size, file count
- Wrote t-sql queries for finding actual size of database, compressed size of database, growth rate and made reports based on that values
- Created SSIS Packages for offline replication and incremental load
- Wrote SQL code for finding errors on every server and resolution of errors
- Replication setup and coding for transfer records between replicated servers
- Implemented Change Tracking in large databases
- Binary Data Transfer using different techniques
- Truncate DB for migration Data
- Worked with merge replication in Database servers located in different location and maintain both servers everyday by solving issues in replication
- Average row count per day report in live servers for Finding **DB Growth**
- Created SSIS Package to find differences in Development and UAT environment
- Worked on **Documentation** using MS word
- Created Data dictionary in SSRS
- Automate email for backup report and System CPU, RAM, DISK usage reports in SSRS
- Technical Problem Solving, Profiler, Performance tuning, Tuning advisor, Partitioning.
- Backup/ Restore, Replication, Log shipping, Mirroring

**Christ Polytechnic Institute.** 

November 2010- May 2012

#### Role = Lecturer

#### Responsibilities:

- Taken various subjects like C, C++, Java, DBMS (Database management system) etc
- Guided student regarding admission and query regarding systems
- Maintained college website and social pages
- Contacted previous students to verify information listed on website
- Complete knowledge and Proficiency in Microsoft Suite (Excel, Word and PowerPoint)
- Prepared standard and routine reports, presentations, letters meeting agendas and minutes
- Arranged tours for new students and address their concerns and questions
- Managed everyday class schedule
- Planned technical events for students to grow in their field